-
Speaker 1: Gentleman yields his back. The gentleman from Kentucky is recognized.
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): I thank the chairman. Secretary Mayorkas, the Department of Homeland Security issued a National Terrorism Advisory System Bulletin this year in February. It said the United States remains in a heightened threat environment fueled by several factors, including online environment filled with false or misleading narratives and conspiracy theories and other forms of mis, dis, and malinformation. Can you define malinformation for
us?
-
Speaker 3: Congressman, we're dealing with false information that is used for a particular purpose.
Speaker 5: - Isn't malinformation actually true information that may be inconvenient to the establishment orthodoxy?
- I'm
Speaker 5: sorry, Congressman. - Isn't malinformation a made up word that refers to information that's actually true but just inconvenient
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): to the government narrative?
Speaker 6: - That is not true.
Speaker 6: Let me
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): ask you this. You said that the proliferation of false or misleading narratives so discord and undermine public trust in U.S. government institutions. Is it illegal to undermine public trust in U.S. government institutions?
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): Congressman,
Speaker 4: we become
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): involved because we believe in the
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): First Amendment right, and we have safeguards to protect it. We actually have a statutorily created Office for Civil Rights and Civil
Liberties.
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): We become involved not with respect to a particular ideology. We are ideology neutral, but it's connectivity to violence.
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): Isn't
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): larger government an ideology, the bigger government? Let me ask you my original question. Is it illegal to undermine public trust in U.S. government institutions? Congressman.
- We
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): understand First Amendment
Speaker 9: principles. We embrace and protect them. - Doesn't the-- - Individuals can espouse whatever ideology they believe in. -
And
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): so it's-- - That is a-- - So let me ask you the question, if you just answer it directly. Is it illegal to undermine public trust in U.S. government institutions? Isn't that in fact what we're doing here today? When we point out that you've released a million or two million people into this country without trying to deport them?
I
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): mean, are we in fact undermining
Speaker 10: trust in your institution? Aren't we doing that? And isn't that actually healthy when we point that
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): out? - Congressman, may I share with you what the Department of Homeland Security does with respect to
Speaker 11: ideologies? - I need to ask you another question
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): since you haven't answered any of these yet. You say that there is widespread online proliferation of false or misleading narratives.
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): regarding COVID-19, is the claim that natural immunity is real, is that a false or misleading online narrative?
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): Congressman, we do not evaluate particular ideologies or particular narratives. How about the claim that vaccines don't stop the spread of the virus? Was that a false or misleading COVID narrative?
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): Congressman, what we do is we are involved when there's a connectivity between an ideology, whatever that ideology
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): ...
How about... I'm not talking
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): I'm not talking about ideology, I'm talking about COVID-19. Is the notion that masks were ineffective at stopping transmission, was that a false or misleading
Speaker 11: narrative?
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): - Congressman, allow me to repeat. What we get engaged in is a connectivity to violence. It is our responsibility to prevent violence from occurring. We work
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): very closely. - Is it, I'm just saying, I want you to give me an example of a false or misleading narrative that encouraged violence.
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): that you say that there were,
Speaker 10: that grievances associated with these themes inspired violent extremist attacks during 2021. Did hydroxychloroquine, did that inspire violent extremist attacks? What are you talking about in this document when you say that false or misleading narratives about COVID-19 inspired violent extremist attacks?
Speaker 10: attacks during 2021. Can you give us a single example? I've given you some questions. Was it the narrative that this may have leaked from a lab in China? Was that the thing? And if so, what did it inspire? What's the violence?
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): Congressman, would you like an example? Yeah. Yeah. COVID-19 is caused by 5G cell towers, an attack on a cell
tower.
That
Speaker 8 (lower-pitched voice): attack on a cell tower triggers the involvement of the Department of Homeland Security. That is an example. It is the connectivity to violence.
Speaker 11: We do not condone violence. - You
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): think COVID-19 caused attacks on cell towers? I think you're chasing ridiculous things.
- Mr. Chairman. -
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): People watching this at home? - Mr. Chairman. - Have they gotta be just amazed that you would spouse this? - Will this be allowed to
answer?
Speaker 15: He
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): said that false or misleading narratives about COVID-19 need to be censored. He's implying that they need to be censored because getting out this
Speaker 16: information, the free speech, is somehow dangerous to our country in the context of COVID-19. I completely disagree. He didn't give us an example. Can I yield back the balance? Can he answer the question because he's been
Speaker 18: misquoted? The time belongs to the gentleman. He has yielded back.